

Professional Summary

Over 7 years 10 months of software development, System Administration most of which is on Oracle technologies as Oracle 10g, 9i Application Server, WebForms and Reports, Perl, Core Java, Database Admini and general troubleshooting skills. Good documentation skills.

Skills Profile

_							
_	Δ	_	h	n	_	2	
	┖	•			•	•	

Operating System	Linux RHEL 3.0, Solaris 5.8, 9, 10 Windows 2000, Windows NT, Fedora,Ubuntu
Environment	Oracle 11.5.5 to 11.5.10 (E Business Suite), Oracle 9i AS, 10g Infrastructure, 10g Oracle Application Server, Web Forms and Reports ,IBM Websphere ND
Database	Oracle 8, 8i, 9i ,10g
Internet Tools	Apache, XML, Core Java, Dream Weaver, Perl, Java Script, OEM,Oc4J,Oracle discoverer
Languages	Core Java, Perl, C++, Fortran
Other	Developer 2k,Troubleshooting, Oracle 11i Technology Stack issues, Apps DBA AD UTILS, GL, AP, P2P, O2C

Functional

Management and Leadership Skills	 Worked on Actimize for detecting financial frauds. Worked on Daybreak Lending Software(Mortgage by iFlex Solutions) Worked on Cash Management Software for making modules on Lockboxes and Post Dated Checks.
Training & Development	Training for Apps DBA routine tasks to developers. Core Java, Oracle 9iAS

Professional Experience

Actimize Oracle DBA

10 Sept 07 to Present 11 months +

- Configuration/Installation/Upgrade/patching of database
- Resolving space management issues at table space level, purging logs.



- Supporting multiple projects build requirements using GE standard build procedures.
- Backup and Restore using RMAN, Data Pump
- 24x7 production database maintainance
- Scheduling cron jobs for automated ackups, analyze schema, export, imp dumps, monitoring cron jobs for any new objects being created etc.

Environment: Oracle DB 9i/10g , Sun Solaris 10,9

 \Diamond

Daybreak (onsite Japan)

14Aug 06 to 15 Aug 07

System Administrator, Oracle DBA, App Server

12 months

- Installation, CPU patching, Upgrade of Database
- Space Management issues
- Cloning, export import dumps, data pump
- Produce test plans and reviews with GECF Japan IT teams.
- Understand the installation/Configuration of Websphere ND clustered environment
- Integration between Web sphere, Oracle Application server and Vision Plus mainframe.
- Test Plan/Patching/of Daybreak Lending system, Oracle Application server10gAS, as required and apply patches as released to be tested in the SIT->UAT->PROD cycle.
- HTTPS implementation using OCA in 10g Oracle Infrastructure server and Oracle Application server.
- Document test results and provide necessary quality measurements. Provide RCAs (Root cause Analysis) for unexpected behaviors and troubleshooting.
- Troubleshooting any Oracle DB/Forms issues in Daybreak Lending Suite
 Environment: Web sphere ND 6, Oracle 10g RAC db (2 node), Sun Solaris, Win 2003 server

 \Diamond

Metro Politan Housing Trust, UK

22nd Feb 05 to 5th June 05

Apps Consultant

5 months

As Apps Consultant I was required to work on integrating Discoverer 11i Workbooks from 11.5.9 to be seen through Oracle 10g Portal using 10g Discoverer.

- Installation of 10g Infrastructure along with 10g Application Server and integrating it with Oracle 11i
- Implementation of Discoverer PortletProvider in Oracle 11i
- Support for Development Team on Oracle 11i env over HP/UX

Environment: HP UX Operating system, Oracle 10g Application Server, Oracle 10g Infrastructure, Oracle Discoverer, Workbooks, Oracle Portal, Java, Oracle 11i (11.5.9)

Black n Veatch USA

22nd Feb 05 to Jun 05

Apps Consultant

5 months

This was a customisation project for Oracle 11i Development was done using Forms and Reports and Deployed on 11.5.9 instance.

- Apps DBA support Activities on Oracle 11i for development team.
- Troubleshooting issues while implementing iSetup in Oracle 11i
- Instance Migrations

Environment: Oracle 11i (11.5.9), WebForms, Reports, Unix Operating system

Development/Maintenance for Oracle 11i E Business Suite

24th Feb 03 to 25th Ian 05

Apps Engineer/DBA

23 Months

- As Apps Technical person Maintainance of inhouse E business suite instances ranging from 11.5.5 to 11.5.10.
- Development and configuration management of technology stack of Oracle 11i. Especially Apache, Forms and Reports.
- Creating and applying patches on Oracle 11i EBS environment.



- Bug Triaging and resolution
- Installation and Configuration of 11i instances such as Multinode,
- Cloning 11i instances
- Working closly with ADX (Autoconfig) FND team and TXK (Techstack) to deliver changes in configuration templates for 11i
- Upgrade of Apache 1.3.9 to 9iApplication Server 1.0.2.2.2
- Oprocmanager load balancing using AutoConfig
- JDK migration in Oracle 11i from from 1.1.8(11.5.1) to 1.4.2(11.5.10)
- SSL implementation using AutoConfig
- SSO/OID third party partner application of 11.5.10 with 10g bi directional provisioning of users portal schema and ORASSO and SSOSDK

Environment: Linux, Windows, Oracle DB 8, 8i, 9i, 10g, Oracle 9iAS, Apache, Java, Forms, Oracle Internet Directory, Unix Scripts and DOS scripts, OOPS Perl, JavaScripts

Cash@Will (Cash Management Software for Multinational Banks)

15th May 2001 to 10th Feb 2003

Oracle 9iAS, Web Form/ Reports Troubleshooting PDC, Lockboxes in Cash Management

22 Months

- Research for Oracle 9iApplication Server and implementation of web forms using Socket Mode and listener Servlet mode
- Development Role For Post Dated Cheques and Lockbox functionality
- Database Language conversions to UTF-8 for multilingual applications
- Responsible for troubleshooting 9iAS problems in Sun Solaris 8 and on Win NT platforms
- Responsible for performance optimization of 9iAS
- Development in forms 6i Cash@will
- Implementation of File Upload Utility in D2k Forms and Java Importer in SSL Environment
- Responsible for 9i AS Administration, Implementation of HTTPS mode
- Responsible for Solaris 8 Administration
- Implementing Forms Listener Servlet mode

Environment: Sun Solaris 5.8, Developer 2000 Forms and Reports, Windows NT 4.0 server, Windows 2000 Server, Citrix

Summary of Projects

Actimize project - Kanbay- FSSBU Capgemini group Co. GE Money HQ IT

10 Sept 2007 to Present

Oracle DBA (Build/Run)

Actimize is leading software for fraud detection and Anti Money Laundering.

As a build DBA my responsibility was to implement this for 52 countries. And support its distributed world wide team

GE Money Japan (onsite) through Kanbay

14 Aug 2006 to 15 Aug 2007



System Administration, Oracle DBA, Oracle 10gAS

Daybreak Lending management system Installation, Upgradation, COnfiguration and Maintainance. Using forms and reports and their deployment on 10g Application server.

IBM Websphere configuration for integration with VisionPlus.

Kanbay 230ct 05 to 14 Aug 2006

Apps Consultant

Migration of oracle 11i 11.5.9 from Solaris 8 to Solaris 10. Routine install, maintain and configuration of oracle servers

Metro Politan Housing Trust, UK

22nd Feb 05 to 5th Jun 05

Apps Technical Consultant

This project was a project for Discoverer Reports in Oracle 11i environment. Requiring the integration of Portal with Oracle 10g with Discoverer and upgrading the Work Book Reports.

Black n Veatch USA

22nd Feb 05 to 5th Jun 05

Apps Technical Consultant

This was a customization project for Oracle 11i Manufacturing module. Development was done using Forms and Reports and Deployed on 11.5.8 instance. Applications cloning as per Clients requirements, Applying database and Applications Patches

Development/Maintenance for Oracle 11i E Business Suite

24th Feb 03 to 25th Jan 05

Apps Engineer/Apps DBA

We were responsible for coordinating the breadth of technologies used by the Oracle Applications suite of ERP and CRM products. Installation and customization of Applications and pre-release testing of all Applications major and interim releases.

Cash@Will (Cash Management Software for Multinational Banks) 15th May 2001 to 10th Feb 2003

Software Engineer (Research and Development)

Cash@Will as a project for Citibank Singapore built using Developer 2000 Forms and Reports and being implemented on 3 tier architecture using Oracle 9i AS has the capability to handle multicountry, multi-currency, multi-bank and multi-lingual transactions. The system was able to handle 2 lacs Transactions per day.

Training and Seminars

- Oracle 10g RAC by Wilshire Technologies Hyderabad.
- Oracle Financials (GL,AP,AR,FA,CM) by Genesis Software Systems, Hyderabad.
- QA procedures in Oracle Corp. (SPMP, Matrices Collections, templates etc
- Server Concepts by Oracle Corp
- Application Object Library (AOL) Coding Standards 11i by Oracle Corp
- Oracle Applications (OA) Frameworks 11i by Oracle Corp
- Oracle 9i AS training by Oracle Corp
- Software Engineering and Quality Assurance at Nucleus Software Exports Ltd
- Configuration Management at Nucleus software
- CMM guidelines
- NSSP guidelines
- Team Building by Indus management consultants.
- Code Walk through
- Creating winning organisations IMA Bridgestone National Convention)
- Alliance Francaise French Language (6 months course)
- KNOPPIX 3.3



- Core Java by SQL Star
- AOL standards
- Oracle 10g New features

Certifications

Pursuing SCJP Certification

Diploma in French Language from Alliance Francaise.

Education

Master of Management Science, IIPS, Devi Ahilya University Indore, May 2001 Bachelor of Engineering Technology, SGSITS, Devi Ahilya University, Indore June 1998

Professional Organizations

Kanbay FSSBU - Capgemini Group Company , October 2005 to Present iGate Global, February 2005 to June 2005
Oracle IDC, February 2003 to Jan 2005
Nucleus Software Exports, May 2001 to Feb 2003
NetCom Services, August 1998 to Aug 1999